Joel T. Goguen

https://jgoguen.ca joel@jgoguen.ca

SUMMARY

Information Security generalist and software developer with over a decade of experience across a range of Information Security topics. Focus on providing an exceptional user experience while protecting business assets and setting up future success.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science

University of New Brunswick, Fredericton, NB, Canada

Procedural and object-oriented programming

· Software Engineering

· Database design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mongodb, Inc. NEW YORK CITY, NY, USA

Senior Site Reliability Engineer

- · Own back-end services, infrastructure components, and software code
- Develop capacity plans for scaling up to very large distributed systems across multiple cloud providers
- Document security requirements and decisions and identify future work
- · Minimize differences between the general and FedRAMP-compliant environments

- Monitor service health, stability, performance, and security across multiple cloud providers
- Analyze and resolve issues with very large-scale systems across multiple cloud providers
- Evaluate security requirements and assist with identifying tradeoffs

META PLATFORMS, INC. MENLO PARK, CA, USA

Security Engineer

March 2018 - September 2023

September 2023 - Present

May 2010

- Assess and enhance security of core infrastructure and client laptops and desktops
- · Design and develop tools and automation to improve the security of corporate infrastructure and client devices
- Design and develop a system using X.509 client certificates to safeguard access to internal data and systems
- · Drove assessment, selection, and implementation of the corporate password manager solution
- · Assess the security of new technologies and products and provide recommendations for improvements

Production Engineer June 2014 - March 2018

- Owned back-end services, infrastructure components, and software code
- · Developed capacity plans for scaling up to very large distributed systems
- · Work within PCI- and SOX-compliant environments to ensure all changes maintain compliance status
- Document security requirements and decisions and identify future work
- · Monitor service health, stability, performance, and security
- · Analyze and resolve issues with very large-scale systems
- · Evaluate security requirements and assist with identifying tradeoffs
- · Drove efforts to overhaul security and access models for automated remediation systems

University of New Brunswick

FREDERICTON, NB, CANADA

May 2010 - May 2014

System Administrator / Developer

university intranet portal

- Developed a campus map system based on the

· Configured, administered, and maintained the

- Google Maps API · Managed and integrated CAS and Shibboleth Sin-
- gle Sign-On services
- Developed integrations between the university intranet portal and other applications
- · Contributed to the development and maintenance of an online university program application system in use by university admissions and prospective students around the world
- Design, develop, and maintain web-based applications and web services with strict privacy and security requirements

- Worked with the Hannon Hill Cascade Content Management System
- Developed Perl and PHP applications to support the needs of the university community
- · Worked with the Enterprise Solutions team and the UNB community at large to gather and analyze software requirements
- · Analyze and resolve issues with enterprise software, working with departmental experts as required
- · Created and maintained internal standards for software development and system administration

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, XML, CSS, JavaScript, and JSON
- · Linux as both client and server
- · macOS and Windows clients
- · Iptables and PF firewalls

- · Python and Golang
- · OpenBSD as client and server
- OpenSSH server
- · MySQL and PostgreSQL databases

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Work unsupervised for extended periods of time
- Work well in a team or independently
- Able to identify work to be done and prioritize execution
- · Self-motivated with excellent work ethic